Imagine that the person who remembers every small household detail is unavailable for three days.
Good intentions are not enough when school pick up, pet care, an elder check-in,
a bill reminder, and trusted home access all depend on one person.
This is Sahaaya, a family continuity planner built for the OpenAI Build Week apps for your life category.
It turns a short household brief into a clear, family-owned continuity plan.
For this demo, every person and fact is fictional.
First, Sahaaya maps five responsibilities and attaches each one to a cited source fact.
It also identifies the questions that the family still needs to answer.
Next, we rehearse a 72-hour absence.
The planner surfaces an availability collision before anyone relies on the plan,
and it explicitly excludes passwords, payment credentials, and door codes.
The key design principle is human control.
Sahaaya proposes assignments, but every responsibility stays pending until a person explicitly approves it.
Compilation remains blocked until all five decisions are made.
After approval, Sahaaya produces separate candidate checklists for the people involved.
It then runs deterministic checks, exact responsibility count, known evidence citations,
allowed assignments, explicit approvals, and the fictional replay boundary.
ASHA-256 receipt makes the demonstrated plan reproducible.
Codex accelerated the product workflow, architecture, tests, and browser verification.
An optional server-only GPT-5.6 proof uses the responses API with structured outputs and storefalls.
GPT-5.6 helps extract grounded suggestions.
Deterministic application code remains responsible for approvals,
verification, and export. Sahaaya never sends messages, triggers emergency services,
or offers medical, legal, financial, or safeguarding advice.
It is a planning aid for a calm, human-reviewed handoff.
Sahaaya, when you cannot be there, your circle knows what to do.